《星际迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
向在通讯范围内的所有联邦星舰求救
To any Federation vessels in range, need help.
遭遇戈恩人袭击
Under attack by the Gorn.
如今星际联邦和戈恩霸权的关系非常紧张
The Federation's at a dangerous point in our relationship with the Gorn Hegemony.
这看起来像是一条分界线
It looks like a demarcation line.
帕纳索斯贝塔星和他们所有的武装力量
With Parnassus Beta and all their forces
在这条线的另一边
on the far side of the line.
不幸的是 我认为我们的人
Unfortunately, that is where
被关押在那里
I believe our people are being held.
我不打算丢下他们不管
I don't plan on leaving them behind.
如果我头脑里藏着的东西是拯救进取号的答案
If somewhere in my head is the answer to saving the Enterprise,
那我必须冒这个险
then that's a risk I have to take.
拿着这个
Take this.
它能帮你藏起来
It'll help you hide.
快跑
Run!
在下蒙哥马利·斯考特
Montgomery Scott at your service.
你怎么还活着
How are you not dead?
我知道如何隐藏在众目睽睽之下
Well, I figured out how to hide in plain sight.
你造了个戈恩人的应答器吗
You built a Gorn transponder?
总的来说 对于扫描仪而言
Eh, basically, to a scanner,
我们的穿梭机看起来像是戈恩飞船
the shuttle looked like a Gorn ship.
你还能再造一个类似之前的设备吗
Could you build another device like the one you made?
发生什么了
What's happening?
巴特尔舰长需要马上注射镇定剂
Captain Batel is in need of immediate sedation.
昨天发生的
Happened yesterday.
我不会放弃她的
I'm not giving up on her.
我也没那个打算
I have no intention of doing that.
舰长 传送机目前在星球表面上未探测到任何人
Captain, the transporter is not currently picking up anyone on the surface.
艾普里尔上将命令我们马上撤离
Admiral April's ordering our immediate withdrawal.
殖民地居民和外勤队
The colonists and the landing party
显然被传送到了
appear to have been beamed up
戈恩人的船上
by the Gorn.
舰长 请下令
Orders, Captain?
现在 即将揭晓结局
And now, the conclusion.
舰长 请下令
Orders, Captain?
护盾只剩50%了
Shields at 50%.
舰长
Captain.
舰长 请下令
Orders, Captain?
乌乎拉 再重复一下上将刚刚的命令
Uhura, repeat April's last order.
撤退 并且
Retreat and rendez...
撤退并与舰队汇合 舰长
Retreat and rendezvous with the fleet, sir.
他给了坐标
He gave coordinates.
但他没说要立即汇合 对吧
But he didn't say immediately?
行了 各位有什么点子吗
All right, who's got ideas?
声东击西
Diversionary tactics.
我们被围困得太厉害了
We're too boxed in.
排空曲速舱 制造一片等离子云团?
Vent the nacelles, create a cloud?
那我们自己也看不见了
We need to be able to see.
干扰敌方的通讯
Jam their comms
使其无法协调攻击
so they can't coordinate attacks.
对 就是这个
That's it. That's the one.
戈恩人使用光信号作为舰对舰通讯手段
The Gorn use light for ship-to-ship messaging.
我正在调整偏导阵列来发射光谱
I'm modulating the deflector array to emit a spectrum.
应该能迷惑他们一阵
Should confuse them for a bit.
好 现在想想要怎么把自己人传送回来
All right, now how do we beam our people back to Enterprise?
扫描显示戈恩星舰能够阻断传送
Scans indicate the Gorn ships are transport-resistant.
所以即便我们绕过了护盾
So, even if we get past the shields,
也需要授权码才行
we need authorization codes.
没时间去破解密码了
No time to hack codes.
先撤再救
Retreat and rescue.
这是一堆烂选项里最好的了
It's the best of a bunch of bad options.
那我们要怎样追踪一艘
So how do we track this specific ship
跨越数光年的船呢
across light-years of space?
沃凯矿 一种稀有元素
Wolkite. A rare element
含有子空间规范玻色子
that contains subspace gauge bosons.
如果我们调整一个定位信标
If we modified a homing beacon...
戈恩人远远地就能看到信标飞过来
The Gorn would see a beacon coming from a mile away.
如果是鱼雷就不会
Not if it's a torpedo.
我们对他们发射一颗哑弹
We tag 'em with a dud.
戈恩人猜不到我们要干什么
The Gorn won't know what we're up to.
护盾只剩30%了
Shields at 30%.
要想这个方法奏效 我们仍需穿透
For this to succeed, we still need to penetrate
戈恩星舰的护盾系统
the Gorn's defensive systems.
我们已经用上了所有武器攻击他们
We've been hitting them with everything we've got,
没多大用
it doesn't do much.
能量护盾基于谐波运作
Uh, energy shields work on harmonics.
如果我们找对频率
If we find the right frequency...
我们可以撞击敌舰
We can ram the ship.
确实
Indeed.
我们的护盾和他们的接触时
When our shields make contact with theirs,
两列谐波叠加时会出现相消干涉现象
they will create a destructive interference pattern
并在短时间内中断这两个频率的护盾
and momentarily interrupt both frequencies.
没有护盾 我们就是活靶子
With our shields down, we'd be sitting ducks.
那我们就只有一次机会
We'd only have one shot.
这就足够了
That's all we need.
米歇尔 调转方向
Mitchell, bring us around,
与敌方驱逐舰正面交火
head-to-head with the destroyer.
是时候来点硬碰硬了
Time to play a game of chicken.
全舰注意 做好冲击准备
All decks, prepare for impact.
随时可让脉冲引擎全速推进 舰长
Full impulse on your orders, Captain.
让惯性阻尼器最大功率运行
Inertial dampeners to maximum.
所有人 抓稳扶好了
Everybody hold onto something.
乌娜
Una...
动手吧
let's hit it.
发射鱼雷
Fire torpedoes.
舵手 曲速带离
Helm, warp us out of here.
遵命
On it.
坚持住 各位
Hang in there, guys.
舰长 我们已到达汇合点
Captain, we've arrived at the rendezvous point.
联邦星舰巴勃罗·毕加索号在联络我们
The USS Pablo Picasso is hailing to greet us.
是艾普里尔上将 舰长
It's Admiral April, sir.
他现在要传送上舰听取汇报
He's beaming aboard now to debrief.
还要打针吗
More needles?
没错 得再来几针
Yes, just a few more pokes.
没有这些
I mean, without these,
你的身体会在静滞场里面坏死 所以
your body will go necrotic in the stasis field, so...
你会变紫 会很难看
Things turn purple. It's not pretty.
我从没被冻结冬眠过
I've never been frozen solid before.
这前景不怎么激动人心
It's not an exciting prospect.
没事 等我们解决了这小小的戈恩卵感染问题
Well, as soon as we work out this little Gorn infection,
你就又能活蹦乱跳的了
you'll be up and around again.
* 原文是指小说《瑞普·凡·温克尔》里主人公一觉睡了二十年 醒来发现世界已经天翻地覆
感觉我会像小说里瑞普那样 一醒来发现一切都变了
So this could be like a Rip Van Winkle thing for me.
我觉得你更会像是睡美人
I see you more as a Sleeping Beauty.
听着 我之前说的是认真的
Listen, I meant what I said before.
一旦那时要在我和其他船员之间做出选择
The moment it looks like me or the crew,
就牺牲掉我
you take me out.
不要想这些了
Don't think about that.
静滞状态会阻止你和戈恩胚胎
Stasis will prevent you and the Gorn
进行任何形式的细胞生长
from any type of cellular growth.
做好最坏的打算
There's another side to the coin.
无论代价如何
Whatever it takes.
无论代价如何 我保证
Whatever it takes. I promise.
我现在要给你注射镇静剂了
I'm, uh, I'm gonna give you a sedative now.
等你醒来 戈恩感染的问题就治好了
And when you wake up, you will be Gorn-free.
肾上腺素和中和剂 快
Epinephrine and neutralizer, stat!
她的身体正在排斥血清
Her body's rejecting the serum.
医务室呼叫舰桥
Sickbay to bridge.
有个最新消息 情况不太乐观
Uh, I have an update, and it's not good.
告诉我最坏情况
Bottom line it for me.
巴特尔舰长对低温血清过敏
Captain Batel is allergic to cryoserum.
我们不能把她放进静滞状态
We can't put her in stasis.
那她的生命已经进入倒计时了吗
So she's back on a ticking clock?
她身体里的戈恩卵会在
The Gorn will hatch from her body in, um...
一天之内孵化
in less than a day.
我正在努力寻找治疗的方法
I'm stuck trying to find a treatment.
但是
Um... uh...
也许如果约瑟夫在这里 就可以
maybe if Joseph was here, I could...
我会派人去帮忙
I'm sending help.
克莉丝汀
Christine...
我相信你
I believe in you.
救救她
Help her.
我会尽我所能 舰长
I'll do my best, Captain.
舰长 我或许不是医生
Captain, I may not be a doctor,
但我能够把我所有的能力都奉献在巴特尔舰长的治疗上
but I will dedicate all of my abilities to Captain Batel
直到解决她的戈恩卵感染
until her Gorn infection is... resolved.
就只是看着?
Just stand by?
你可是有一整支舰队在待命啊
You have the entire fleet out there ready to go.
这是力量展示
It's a show of force.
我们先要建立起有效的巡逻
First we need to establish patrols.
他们真这么觉得吗
Do they really think
觉得戈恩人只要炸完这些殖民地
the Gorn are just gonna stop and go home
就会收手然后回家?
after they raided those colonies?
好吧 这是很棘手的情况
Look, it's a tough situation,
但我们必须一次解决一个问题
but we have to manage it one piece at a time.
无数无辜生命正危在旦夕 鲍勃
There are innocent lives at stake, Bob.
我明白
And I get that.
但这件事发生在我们的管辖范围之外
But it's happening outside of our jurisdiction.
拜托 鲍勃
Oh, come on, Bob.
除了你那不怕死的狗斗之外
Apart from your reckless dogfight,
这些攻击和联邦并没有关系
these attacks do not involve the Federation.
我们有规定的 克里斯
We have regulations, Chris.
所以 就因为死的不是联邦公民
So, because it's non-Federation citizens that are dying,
我们就作壁上观吗
we do nothing?
我们对于联邦成员国都有义务在身
We have an obligation to our member worlds.
那可是数十亿人
Billions of lives.
现在就贸然投入战争
To rush into a fight right now
会将所有人都置于危险当中
puts all of them at risk.
我们不能这样
We can't do it.
我们还没从克林贡战争中完全恢复
We're still recovering from the Klingon War.
你说得一点没错
You are absolutely right,
戈恩就是利用这一点发动进攻
and the Gorn sense our weakness.
我们现在是猎物
We are prey.
他们只会把这条霸权的边境线
They will push this Hegemony line
向着联邦领空内部推得越来越深
further and further into Federation space.
你也知道他们会这么做
And you know they will.
等到我们真的恢复过来
And by the time we actually get around
有精力反制的时候
to doing something about it...
一切就太晚了
it'll be way too late.
我听说了外勤队的事
I heard about the landing party.
对啊 还有几百号殖民地居民呢
Yeah, and a couple hundred colonists, too.
玛丽呢
And Marie?
她在医务室里
She's in sickbay.
官方地说 给你的命令是监控分界线
Officially, your orders are to monitor the demarcation line
避免戈恩人的进一步进犯
for any encroachment by the Gorn.
好 那不官方的呢
Okay. And unofficially?
为何不给他们点颜色看看 告诉他们我们不是猎物
How do we punch back and show them we aren't prey?
行 我接受这个
Yeah, I can do that.
你做的这个装置
This contraption of yours,
你再说一遍它是干什么的
what's it supposed to do again?
发射极化电磁信号
Emit a polarized EM signature that
诱骗戈恩 让它们以为我们是他们中的一员
tricks the Gorn into thinking we're one of them.
类似隐身装置的原理
It's like a cloaking device.
那么它究竟是怎么做到这一点的
And how, exactly, does it do that?
说实话 我不太记得了
Ah, if I'm being honest, I don't really remember.
我就是当时灵机一动
I was kind of in the moment.
很好 那我现在要问一个很蠢的问题
Well, now I'm going to ask a silly question,
而且我确定我知道答案
to which I'm pretty sure I know the answer.
别又来这个
Not this again.
就像回到了报告厅一样
It's like being back in lecture hall.
你怎么知道 你又没去过报告厅
How would you know that? You were never there.
我去过 在后排而已
I was there, in the back.
你在把这堆东西拼起来时
Did you record a work-in-progress log
有没有记工作日志
while you were jury-rigging this up?
啥 您的意思是在戈恩人正在轰炸我的时候记录?
What, you mean as the Gorn were tearing our ship apart?
斯考特 工程学第一定律就是写下来
First rule in engineering, Scotty: write it down.
我们被要求无论什么情况下
There's a reason we track our work
都要记录自己的工作是有理由的
no matter what the circumstance, and this,
现在的这个情况 就是最好的理由
this right now, this is precisely the reason.
抱歉打断
Pardon the interruption.
你们还要多久能让这东西恢复运作
How long before you get that working?
哦 派克舰长 问题是
Oh, Captain Pike, the thing is,
它在我的小穿梭机上能起作用
it worked on my wee shuttle,
但进取号就
but the Enterprise is...
那您什么时候需要它呢 舰长
How soon do you need it, Captain?
我们正在航向戈恩的领空
We're headed into Gorn space,
所以现在能用就最好了
so now would be good.
在我们跨过分界线之前它会准备好的
It'll be up and working before we cross the Hegemony line.
我希望如此 因为我和船上所有人的命都指望在它身上了
I'm counting on it, as are the lives of everyone on board.
不管有没有这个装置
We're going after our missing crew,
我们都要去搜救被抓走的船员
with or without that device.
明白了吗
Understand?
哇 还真是一点压力都没有呢
Well, that's no pressure.
妈妈
Mom?
拉安 勇敢点
La'An, be brave.
对危险没有畏惧之心才会置你于死地
Not believing you're gonna die is what gets you killed.
那是戈恩人
It's the Gorn.
醒醒
Wake up.
快醒醒
Wake up!
你能做到的
You can do this.
第一个倒霉的总是医生
Always start with the doctor.
好了
Okay.
我的妈 我的手
Holy crap, my hand!
我他妈的半只手都没了
Half my hand is frickin' gone.
艾丽卡 看着我
Erica, look at me.
看着我 冷静下来
Look at me. Relax.
会没事的
It's going to be okay.
只要我们能回到船上就能治好它
We can fix this when we get back to the ship.
拜托
Please.
先保持冷静
Try to stay calm.
好吧
Okay.
但怎么
How?
我们怎么才能回到船上
How do we get back to the ship?
而且他们怎么办
What about them?
如果我们一次只能解救一个人
If we free them one at a time,
那我们能救出来的人屈指可数
we'll only get a handful out.
如果能的话
If that.
光是我们四个人脱困就花了这么久
Look how long it took for the four of us to get loose.
这是一个巨大的消化腔
This is a massive digestive chamber.
而且它正在消化
And it's working its way through...
看起来像是燃料加工厂
looks like a-a processing plant for fuel.
或者只是戈恩人的食物工厂
Or just food for the Gorn.
我真的不想变成哪个戈恩人的盘中餐
I don't like the idea of being anyone's lunch.
即便我们能够唤醒他们
And even if we can wake them up,
不管是一个还是一百个
one or a hundred,
我们还是没法离开这个
we still don't have a way out of...
不知道什么的地方
wherever this is.
先一步一步来吧
One step at a time.
要是什么都不做 就是等死
Sitting here doing nothing is a death sentence.
而且搞不好
And for all we know,
那些戈恩人可能在我们醒来那会就被惊动了
the Gorn were alerted the moment that we woke up.
所以那些杀人蜥蜴可能已经在来的路上了
So the killer lizards could already be on their way.
他们来了
They're coming.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
拉安
La'An.
无论发生什么
No matter what.
拉安
La'An.
上尉 你在想什么
What's on your mind, Lieutenant?
你说得对
You're right.
不仅仅关乎我们自己
It's not just about us.
这些殖民地居民很快也会被杀害
All of these people will be dead soon.
看这
Hey.
这看起来像个排泄桩
This looks like an evacuation pile.
也许 这艘船不能处理的东西 都由它排出
Maybe whatever the ship can't process, it expels.
粪堆里的武器
Weapons from a crap pile.
怪了 这个方向是对的
Strangely, it's a step in the right direction.
我不想只救下屈指可数的人
I don't want to save a handful of colonists,
我想拯救全部人
I want to save them all.
所有还活着的人 都能回家
Everyone that's still alive gets home.
即使这意味着 我们必须杀出一条血路
Even if we have to shoot our way out.
哎呀 你个蠢货
Ack, bawheid.
不是这样
That's not it.
是戈恩人 他们来了
They're here!
该死
Oh, shite.
我们完蛋了 斯考提
We're doomed. Scotty.
不不不不
No, no, no, no...
我们都死定了
We're all gonna die!
成功了
It's working.
快通知舰桥 把它加到护盾上
Tell the bridge to patch it to the shields.
怎么 太晚了吗
What? Is it too late?
舰桥呼叫科学实验室 你们进展如何了
Bridge to science lab. What's the status down there?
我们马上要进入戈恩领空了
We're about to enter Gorn space.
真是狡猾
Oh, you minx.
已经在正常运行了 舰长
It's up and running, Captain.
我们现在就能把它加到护盾上
We can patch it into the shields now.
好极了 派克完毕
Excellent. Pike out.
一点都不好笑
That wasn't funny.
明明就很有趣
It was fun.
你差点害我心脏病发作
You nearly gave me a heart attack.
我那么做 是因为我了解你
I did it 'cause I know you.
你才不了解呢
No, you don't.
太了解了 平时闲得发慌的时候你就摆了
Yes, with too much time on your hands, you fall apart,
但要是有相位枪顶着你的头 你立刻精神百倍
but put a phaser to your head and voilà.
你管我这么多干嘛
Why do you care what I do?
你防备太重了 斯考提
You put up walls, Scotty.
你太害怕承担风险了
You're too afraid to take a risk.
我修好了你想让我修的东西
I fixed what you wanted me to.
而且你相当目无上级
And you're insubordinate to boot.
准确来说你又不是我的上级
Well, technically you're not my C.O.
她在驭星号上牺牲了
She went down on the Stardiver.
我可以离开了吗 长官
May I be excused, sir?
哦 斯考提
Oh, Scotty.
舰长 我们正在接近戈恩霸权领空边境
Approaching the Hegemony demarcation line now, sir.
脱离曲速
Drop us out of warp.
开启斯考特的应答器
Start Mr. Scott's transponder.
应答器?
Transponder?
佩利亚说它更像是一个改装过的电磁脉冲发射器
Pelia says it's more like a modified EM pulse emitter.
好吧 那就说得通了
Okay, then that makes sense.
戈恩人肯定不使用光学数据
The Gorn must not use optical data.
他们已经进化了
They've evolved,
所以他们一定依赖生物识别信息
so they must rely on biometrics,
热量和电磁信号
heat and EM signatures.
嗯 是时候看看这到底能不能成功了
Well, time to see if it actually works.
我的意思是 它应该可以
It should. I mean,
除非哪个戈恩人突然决定看一眼窗外
unless maybe one of them decides to look out a window.
舰长 戈恩狩猎舰正在接近
Captain, Gorn hunters approaching.
保持稳定航线
Keep us steady and on course.
目前为止 我没看到任何窗户
So far, I don't see any windows.
它奏效了
It worked.
乌乎拉 我们还能接收到沃凯矿信标的信号吗
Uhura, do we still have a signal from the wolkite beacon?
是的 舰长
Aye, sir.
信号很弱且在逐渐减弱 但它还在发射信号
It's faint and getting weaker but still there.
有关于他们去向的情报吗
Any intel on where they're headed?
一个未知的双星系统
An uncharted binary star system.
那里的恒星活动
The stellar activity there
是我们前所未见的
is like nothing we've ever seen before.
舵手 设置航线
Helm, plot a course.
舰长 那个星系的辐射高得超出量表
Captain, the radiation in that system is off the charts.
到最后 我们只能使用脉冲引擎
At a certain point, we can only use impulse engines,
进取号的护盾也无法抵挡辐射了
and our shields won't be able to protect us.
了解 那我们快速行动
Understood. We'll make it quick.
米歇尔 曲速七级
Mitchell, warp factor seven.
遵命 舰长
Aye aye, sir.
有趣
Intriguing.
戈恩卵的孵化进程大幅改变了她身体的生物化学结构
The incubation has severely altered her biochemistry.
她的身体现在依赖于戈恩的幼体
Her body is now as dependent
就像戈恩幼体依赖于她
on the Gorn hatchlings as they are on her.
完美的宿主 不可分割
The perfect host, inseparable.
你试过显微减瘤术了吗
Have you tried microscopic debulking?
模拟完毕
Results completed.
这是我最后跑的一次模拟
It's the last simulation I ran.
死亡率为100%
Probability of fatality is 100%.
我做的每一次模拟 结果全都一样
That's the chorus of the day. It's every simulation I've run.
计算机 模拟显微减瘤术的情境
Computer, run scenarios for microscopic debulking
将注射扎多拉提取物纳入模拟变量中
factoring for an infusion of Zadora extract.
正在处理
Processing.
猎户星的街头毒品?
An Orion street drug?
实话说 这真是天才想法
Actually, that's kind of brilliant.
是你教会了我跳出框架去看
You are the one who taught me to look outside of the box.
是「去思考」
It's "think,"
但也差不多
but close enough.
克莉丝汀
Christine.
我知道你想谈谈
I know you want to talk.
我会尽量简短
I will be brief.
我只是想为你离开前
I simply want to apologize
我们之间的结局道个歉
for the way things ended before you left.
我当时情绪有点失控
I reacted poorly.
好了
Apology accepted.
原谅你了
We're good.
失去你的念头
The thought of losing you,
深深困扰着我
it affected me deeply.
我理解
I understand.
事情变得复杂了
This has gotten complicated,
我不擅长应对复杂
and I am not good at complicated.
而我还是要离开三个月
And I am still going away for three months
去和罗杰·科尔比一起学习
to study with Roger Korby.
等我回来 再看看我们的状态吧
When I get back, let's just see where we are then.
所以你是想说
So you are saying that perhaps
也许分开一段时间 对我们有好处吗
some time apart might be good for us?
史波克
Spock.
是的
Yeah.
但不是说
But not like...
作为我们俩的我们
not like "us" us.
只是说
Like...
作为两个个体的我们
us as people.
请别做那些你觉得浪漫的事
Please don't do something you think is romantic,
像是等我之类的
like wait for me or something.
扎多拉提取物情境模拟完毕
Zadora extract scenario completed.
死亡率为100%
Probability of fatality is 100%.
无论我们用什么方法
No matter how we approach this,
巴特尔的人类基因
Batel's human DNA is...
都存在不足
Inadequate.
她的身体进入休克状态
Her body goes into shock,
血压开始下降
blood pressure drops.
最后死亡
And she dies.
哼 人类的身体始终有限
Huh. Human physiology.
但如果我们给她的基因帮点忙呢
What if we gave her some help there?
你已经有主意了
You have an idea.
伊勒利亚人的基因
Illyrian DNA.
乌娜的血液
Una's blood,
基因使其可以实时抵抗感染
it's designed to combat infections in real time.
一剂血清可以给巴特尔的免疫系统来一次大升级
A plasma injection could provide a boost to Batel's immunity.
这样我们就能在不使其休克的前提下
And we could attempt the surgery
尝试进行手术了
without her going into shock.
这样做违反规定
It is against regulation,
但能挽救她的生命
but it could save her life.
计算机 模拟手术结果
Computer, run scenario for surgery
将注射伊勒利亚血清纳入模拟变量中
factoring for a plasma transfusion from an Illyrian blood donor.
处理中
Processing.
你当时是怎么说的来着
How did you put it once?
有些规则就是用来打破的?
Some rules are intended to be broken?
几乎准确无误了
Almost exactly it.
这就是机库
There's the hangar.
好吧
Okay.
大家都了解计划吧
Everyone's clear on the plan?
访问这艘船的计算机主机
Access the ship's mainframe,
上传戈恩星舰的传送器密码
upload the Gorn transporter codes...
把他们带回进取号
Get them to the Enterprise.
要成功 我们必须偷一艘飞船 从这里飞出去
To do that, we have to steal a ship and fly it out of here.
这个看起来没什么警戒措施
That one doesn't look guarded.
我们超有把握 一点都不是不可能任务
Totally got this, not impossible at all.
你什么都能飞 是真的吧
And it's true you can fly anything, right?
别这么没礼貌 当然是真的
Don't be rude. Of course I can.
好
Okay.
来搞定那艘飞船吧
Let's get to that ship.
这是个好计划
This is a good plan.
一定行得通
It's gonna work.
这是个好计划
It's good. It's-it's...
是个好计划 对吗
It's a good plan, right?
当然了
It's a good plan.
没错 我们现在只需要
Yeah. Yeah. Now all we have to do is
别被戈恩人逮住
not get caught by the Gorn.
山姆
Sam.
你为啥要乌鸦嘴
Why would you say that?
不是姐们 这你也能怪我啊
What? Oh, come on, you can't blame me.
相位枪调到击杀档
Phasers to kill.
该走了
Time to go.
我和乌乎拉一直在钻研
Uhura and I have been poring over
手头能得到的戈恩人数据
all available data on the Gorn.
确认的袭击 未被证实的目击
Confirmed attacks, unverified sightings.
如果可能和戈恩人有关系 我们就检查过一遍
If it might be a Gorn, we've checked it out.
比我们想象的信息多出很多
And there's a lot more out there than we thought.
你得稍微用点想象力
You have to squint a little.
但是每一次戈恩目击事件
But every Gorn sighting correlates
都和某个特定的恒星活动规律正相关
to a pattern of specific stellar events.
日冕物质抛射
Coronal mass ejections.
我已经了解过了
I know this already, CMEs.
恒星耀斑爆发会引发强烈恒星风
Stellar flares can set off a frenzy.
是的 其活动遵循一定的规律
Yes, the attacks follow a pattern,
戈恩人的休眠也是如此
but so does Gorn inactivity.
这都是乌乎拉发现的
Uhura is the one who found it.
我们知道有很长一段时间
There are long periods of time
没有任何戈恩人活动的报告
where no Gorn activity is reported.
甚至连一点风声都没有
Not so much as a rumor.
在那个时间段
And in those instances,
独特的恒星活动似乎触发了某些东西
there's unique stellar activity that seems to trigger...
休眠
Hibernation.
没错
Yes.
我们认为戈恩人有着漫长的休眠周期
We believe that the Gorn have a long hibernation cycle.
在适当的条件下 它们会变得温顺
Under the right conditions, they become docile.
我们可以利用这一点
We can use that.
我们的科学团队协助了计算
The science team chipped in on the math
成功识别出X级太阳耀斑及其伴随的上弓下沉流
and was able to isolate the presence of X-class flares
两者在消失前均有明显前兆
and supra-arcade downflows that precede their absence.
做的好 你们俩
Good work, both of you.
还有一点
There's something else.
数据表明
The data also suggests that
我们可能正处于戈恩人长期侵略行为的初期
we could be at the beginning of a long cycle of Gorn aggression.
这些袭击可能预示着
These attacks could signal what
戈恩人即将发动全面入侵
could soon be a full-scale Gorn invasion.
舰长 我们将在两分钟后脱离曲速
Dropping out of warp in two minutes, sir.
谢谢你 米歇尔 我们这就来
Thank you, Mitchell. On our way.
史波克和查普尔知道自己在做什么
Spock and Chapel know what they're doing.
我相信他们
I trust them
会好好利用我的血液
with a couple liters of my blood.
谢谢你
Thank you for that.
他们说这可能是她唯一的机会
They say it may be her only hope.
为了玛丽 他们需要什么我都愿意提供
For Marie, they can take all they want.
这次任务不留存记录
This mission's already off-the-record,
所以也没什么好报告的
so nothing to report.
克里斯
Chris,
听一听你自己的建议吧
take some of your own advice.
要抱有希望
Focus on hope.
伊勒利亚血液供给方案已完成
Illyrian blood donor scenario completed.
死亡概率为86%
Probability of fatality: 86%.
只有这个方案能让她有一线生机
That's the first one that's given her any chance at all.
虽然成功率也不高
Albeit not a very high one.
按理说 不能在这种概率下进行手术
I mean, we can't do the surgery with these odds.
但总算有所进展了 我们继续努力
We're on to something. Let's keep at it.
好的
Indeed.
我们已接近辐射区
We're near the radiation zone.
从现在起 只能使用脉冲引擎
From here on, it's impulse engines only.
米歇尔 你连续工作很久了
Mitchell, you've been running nonstop.
去换班吧
Call for relief.
恕我直言 在把所有人都救回来前
With respect, I'm not leaving the station
我绝不离开岗位
until we get everyone back.
明白了
Copy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我收到了沃凯矿的信号
I have the wolkite signature.
即将接近敌方驱逐舰
We're coming up on the enemy destroyer.
我们多久能追上他们
How soon can we overtake them?
克里斯 我们可能来晚了
Chris, we may be too late.
他们已经进入了辐射区
They've already entered the radiation zone.
如果我们继续深入当前星系
If we go any deeper into this star system,
全体船员都将陷入危险
we put the entire crew at risk.
舵手 立即停船
Helm, full stop.
主屏幕切换为远距离观测画面
Put the long-range visual up on the main screen.
是我的错觉 还是
Is it me, or does it look like
那艘船确实正朝着恒星的方向行驶?
that ship is going to fly right into that star?
我也看到了 简直难以置信
I see it, I don't believe it.
遥测数据已确认 舰长
Telemetry confirms, Captain.
我们必须做点什么
We have to do something.
你看
Look.
他们是失去动力了吗
Did they just lose power?
不是
No.
我认为他们是故意的
I think it was intentional.
但为什么呢
But why?
将全部备用能量传输至护盾
All auxiliary power to the shields.
尽可能争取在辐射区停留的时间
Give me as much time as possible inside that radiation zone.
我们追上去
We're going after 'em.
新一轮日冕物质抛射活动逼近
We've got another CME flare coming.
她快不行了
She's coding.
戈恩幼体正在孵化
The Gorn hatchlings are activating.
有什么东西加速了它们的生长
Something has accelerated their growth.
14%的成功率总比注定的死亡要好
A 14% chance of survival is better than certain death.
准备手术吧
Let's prep her for surgery.
我还能接收到沃凯矿的信号
I'm still getting a ping on the wolkite signal.
我们必须尽我们所能拯救我们的船员
We need to get to our people while we still can.
这里的磁场干扰让导航系统无法运作
The magnetic fields here make navigation impossible.
这就解释了戈恩星舰为何会像失去动力一样
That explains why the Gorn go into a free fall.
他们利用了强重力井来完成大部分机动
They let the intense gravity wells do most of the work.
星际舰队方面没有回复
No response from Starfleet.
都是因为这些辐射
It's all the radiation.
无论是进取号还是双星系统以外的区域
And no visuals on the ship
都无法获得影像反馈
or what's beyond the binary stars.
这种光线折射方式会生成一种自然全息投影
The light bends in a way that creates a natural hologram.
一旦穿过它 就无法被看到了
They're essentially invisible once they pass through it.
形成了绝佳的防御屏障
Makes for a great defense system.
也许那是一种降落程序
Maybe it's a landing sequence.
有没有可能 戈恩母星就在这
Could this be the Gorn homeworld?
如果假设成立 那这就是他们回母星的方法
If it is, that's how they go back to it.
舰长
Captain,
外面有情况
something's moving out there.
屏显
On screen.
一号
Number One.
我计算了他们的轨迹
I've plotted their trajectory.
那些舰船正径直驶向联邦领空
Those ships are headed straight for Federation territory.
警告星际舰队
Warn Starfleet.
只能使用深空通讯中继联络
It's a deep space relay.
我无法确实他们是否收到了讯息
I won't be able to confirm if they receive it.
我们得走了
We need to go.
离开该星系的干扰范围
Get clear of this system's interference.
舰长 如果我们现在失去沃凯矿的信号
Captain, if we lose our lock on the wolkite signal,
我无法保证我们能再次进行追踪
I'm not sure we can reestablish contact.
我们会失去外勤小队和殖民地居民
We'll lose the landing party and the colonists.
我们可以放置一个远程通信浮标
We can drop a long-range communication buoy.
将信号连接到浮标上
Tie a signal to it.
这样我们回来时就能找到他们了
That way we can come back for them.
这是我能想到的最好办法了
It's the best I've got.
就这么做
Do it.
我们必须阻止这场入侵
We have to stop this invasion.
通信浮标已部署
Communication buoy is deployed.
米歇尔 持续锁定敌方舰队
Mitchell, stay on that enemy fleet.
调转舰艏
Bringing her about.
尽快曲速离开这里
As soon as we can, you warp out of here.
全速前进 直到我们能够将警报发给星际舰队
Full throttle until we can alert Starfleet.
现在我们是联邦唯一的指望了
We're the only hope the Federation's got right now.
* 此处查普尔和史波克穿的防护服与《原初系列》1x06 “The Naked Time” 中穿着的防护服是同一样式
计算机 启动隔离模式
Computer, engage quarantine mode.
隔离模式已启动
Quarantine mode engaged.
如果失败的话 这就是法雷奥贝塔的悲剧重演
If this goes sideways, it's, it's Valeo Beta all over again.
* 见《奇异新世界》1x09 联邦星舰游隼号上爆发戈恩寄生疫情 坠毁在法雷奥贝塔五星
戈恩卵疫情在全舰爆发的可能性将会是
The probability of a full-scale Gorn outbreak...
我真的不想知道
I really don't want to know.
查普尔护士 联邦星舰进取号
Nurse Chapel, USS Enterprise...
向患者巴特尔注射
...injecting Patient Batel
实验性血浆溶液
with experimental plasma solution.
有进展吗 少尉
Anything, Ensign?
通讯仍受阻碍 舰长
Still jammed, sir.
戈恩人正在发送干扰信号
The Gorn are transmitting an interference signal.
距我们离开双星系统进入曲速还有多久
How long before we clear these binary stars and go to warp?
时间不够
Not soon enough.
戈恩星舰的航速比我们快得多
Those Gorn ships are moving a lot faster than we are.
等警告发出
By the time we get a signal out,
戈恩舰队已经到达联邦外围成员国的位置了
the Gorn will be right on top of the outer Federation worlds.
他们只能坐以待毙
They're sitting ducks.
米歇尔 我们在戈恩舰队的武器射程内吗
Mitchell, are we in shooting distance of the Gorn?
克里斯
Chris,
你要让进取号对阵整个戈恩舰队吗
Enterprise against an entire armada?
我们根本不是对手
We wouldn't stand a chance.
派克呼叫科学实验室
Pike to science lab.
佩利亚 我需要你到舰桥来
Pelia, I need you on the bridge.
好的 舰长 马上来
Aye, Captain, right away.
你打算做什么
What are you up to?
你和乌乎拉
You and Uhura,
你们之前说恒星耀斑决定了
you said stellar flares can dictate
戈恩人的狩猎和休眠周期
a Gorn's hunting and resting cycles.
确实如此
Right.
我们甚至知道哪种辐射信号
We even know precisely what kind of radiation signature
可以让戈恩人陷入休眠
would tell the Gorn to go to sleep.
舰长 这只是理论上的
Um, sir, that's just a theory.
所以
So...
我们只需要人为制造一场恒星耀斑爆发
...we just need to create a stellar flare.
抱歉打断您 舰长
Oh, forgive me for interrupting,
但我们基本没办法对恒星造成什么影响
but you cannot make a star do much of anything.
更别说是精确控制耀斑爆发了
Certainly not precisely, Captain.
所以我们需要自己成为一次日冕物质抛射
Which is why we need to become a CME, uh,
也就是X级耀斑
X-flare ourselves.
舰长 你看
Captain, look.
抱歉 你介意腾位置吗
Uh, sorry, do you mind?
嗯是 用星舰来操作
Eh, sure, using the ship
的确能让我们精准调控发射的辐射和电磁信号
would allow us to modulate the exact radiation and EM signals we'd emit.
但你说的基本上就是
But you're basically talking about
把整艘船变成一颗人造恒星
turning the ship into an artificial star.
这基本上是不可能的
That's-that's nearly impossible.
但并非完全不可能
But not impossible.
为了达到这个目的 我们必须深入到
To do that, we'd have to go deeper
这个致死的辐射区里
into this deadly radiation zone,
径直飞过外面那对双星之间
fly right between those binary stars out there,
想办法制造一个对抗磁场
and create some kind of competing magnetic field
将粒子从双星中引开
to draw particles away from both of them.
需要调整偏导护盾 通讯阵列 还有
Modify the deflector shields, comms array, and, well...
基本上系统都得重改一遍
every-everything else, really.
连舰体都要磁化 才能吸引恒星物质
Magnetize the hull to attract stellar material.
成功的几率是千分之一
It's one in a thousand we'd get it done right
要么能完成任务要么炸飞自己 看吧
or don't blow ourselves up along the way, and, look.
我也不确定 但我愿意赌一把
Yeah, I don't know. I like those odds.
我们就
We'll just...
在爆炸前把它关闭
...turn it off before we blow up.
就这么办
Get it done.
患者对输血反应良好
Patient is responding favorably to the transfusion.
准备进行第一次手术切口
Ready to make the first incision.
等一下
Wait.
你知道最坏的情况是巴特尔舰长会殉职
You know the most likely outcome is the death of Captain Batel?
我们只是需要一点信心
We just have to have a little faith.
或许我们是从错误的角度来看待这件事的
Perhaps we are looking at this from the wrong perspective.
与其在治疗巴特尔上花时间
Instead of operating on Batel,
要是我们试着去对付一下戈恩人呢
what if we treated the Gorn inside of her?
它们想要孵化出来觅食
We know they emerge to feed.
要是我们给它们喂食呢
What if we feed them?
把它们喂饱 防止它们孵化
Satiate them to keep them from coming out.
当他们不再处于攻击状态时 把它们干掉
And when they are no longer in defensive mode, dissolve them.
并用乌娜的伊勒利亚血浆
And use Una's Illyrian plasma
来对抗他们在重新吸收过程中
to fight the multitude of infections that will result
产生的大量感染
from their reabsorption.
没错
Yes.
但我们没有时间再去模拟一次了
But we don't have enough time to run another simulation.
就像你刚才提议的那样
As you suggested,
也许我们只是需要一点信心
perhaps we just need a little faith.
我们甩掉他们了吗
Did we lose them?
或许吧
Maybe,
即便甩掉了 也是暂时的
but if so, then not for long.
这是个接口
This is an interface.
在戈恩的繁殖星球上
They had them on the Gorn...
也有这样的装置
the Gorn breeding planet.
我哥哥马努 他
My brother Manu, he...
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
无论如何 别停下来
Keep moving, no matter what.
嘿
Hey.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
你现在在这里 而不是在过去的那个地方
You're here now, not back there.
是啊 但这里也没好到哪去 不是吗
Yeah, but here's not great either, is it?
是啊 确实很糟糕
No, I suppose not.
我有印象了 让我试试看
I remember. Let me try something.
太神奇了
This is amazing.
我很想把这个拆开 弄明白它是怎么运作的
I'd love to take this apart, figure out how it works.
真是好主意
Yeah, good idea.
在这待上一天慢慢研究吧
Let's make a whole day of it.
吃点零食 在这闲逛
Get snacks, hang out.
那些看起来像是缓冲信号
Those look like buffer signatures.
是的 还有传送授权码
They are. And the transport codes.
如果我们能把这个送回进取号
If we can get this to the Enterprise,
就能救走殖民地的居民
then we can save the colonists.
拯救所有人
All of them.
大伙们
Guys...
快去船上
Get to the ship!
我们就位了
We are in position,
正在接近双星
approaching the binary stars.
当我们关闭电磁脉冲发生器的瞬间
The moment we shut down the EM emitter,
每一艘戈恩星舰都会直奔我们而来
every single Gorn ship is going to come at us.
就像飞蛾扑火一样
Like moths to a flame.
这也正是我们想要的效果
Which is exactly what we want.
大家准备好了吗
Everybody ready?
像太阳一般闪耀吧
Make us shine like the sun.
驾驶位
The pilot seat.
让我坐驾驶位
Put me in the pilot seat.
我来驾驶它
Put me in the pilot seat!
别逞强了
Forget about it!
我能让它飞起来 这非我不可
I can fly it. It has to be me.
她说得对 我们必须得离开这
She's right. We need to go.
我们完全暴露在β粒子和伽马射线中了
We're covered in beta particles and gamma rays.
星舰正在承受着临界水平的辐射
This ship is hitting critical levels of radiation!
戈恩人在做什么
What are the Gorn doing?
他们已经脱离编队
They have broken ranks,
目前正处于进取号的拦截航线上
currently on intercept course with Enterprise.
目前看起来一切顺利
All right, so far, so good.
现在看看它们会不会向我们开火
Now let's see if they shoot at us.
舰长 我收到了一个
Captain, I have a signal bouncing off
通讯信标反射的信号
the communications beacon.
是拉安 长官
It's La'An, sir.
进取号 能收到吗
Enterprise, are you there?
拉安 你在哪
La'An, where are you?
在路上 如果能收到信号的话
On our way. If you can read me,
注意接收我向你们发送的传送密码
I'm sending you transport codes.
把帕纳索斯人传送出去
Beam the Parnassians out.
我们正在尝试传送
We're trying to beam you out,
但我们难以锁定你们
but we're having trouble getting a lock.
你们收到了吗
Do you copy?
它们正冲着我们来
They're gaining on us!
进取号 你们是否收到
Enterprise, do you read me?
把帕纳索斯人传送回舰
Beam the Parnassians out.
舰长 舰体完整性即将逼近极限
Captain, hull integrity is approaching critical failure!
把它关掉 关掉它
Turn it off. Turn it off!
起作用了吗
Did it work?
没错 舰长 最后一艘戈恩船只已返回母星
Aye, sir, the last of the Gorn have gone home.
帕纳索斯人呢
What about the Parnassians?
我们及时把他们传回来了吗
Did we get them out in time?
是的 舰长
Yes, Captain.
拉安的传送密码生效了
The transport codes from La'An worked.
几百名殖民地居民已经被救回
Several hundred colonists accounted for
正在送往应急医务室
and headed for the overflow infirmary.
舰长 我们急需--
Captain, we need immediate as--
将我们传送上舰并让一个医疗小组待命
Beam us out and have a medical team standing by.
派克呼叫轮机部
Pike to Engineering?
是 舰长 我们正在使用传送码
Aye, Captain, we're using the transport codes
破解戈恩狩猎舰的系统
to hack into the Gorn hunter,
应该很快就能搞定
should be just a moment.
克里斯 我们做到了
Chris. Chris, we did it.
我们引起了戈恩人的长时休眠
We triggered a long hibernation in the Gorn.
是啊
Yeah...
但我忍不住在想
But I can't help wondering
我们会不会只是把麻烦推给了未来的人们
if we didn't just create a problem for someone else to solve later.
舰长 我收到了艾普里尔上将的加密呼叫
Captain. I'm getting a secure channel from Admiral April.
接通
Put him through.
克里斯 我们刚收到你的优先级讯息
Chris. We just got your priority message.
在戈恩舰队到这之前我们还有多少时间
How much time do we have before the Gorn ships get here?
请忽略最后一条讯息
Ignore last transmission.
至少在一段时间内我们见不着戈恩人
We won't be seeing the Gorn, at least not for a while.
你有几分把握
How certain are you?
怎么说呢 我已经对戈恩人还以颜色了
Let's just say I found a way to punch back.
保持清醒 别晕过去
Stay with me. Stay with me.
我做的很棒
I did good.
不是吗
Didn't I?
别说话了 你能撑住的
Stop. You're going to make it.
想干掉我 他们还不够格
They'll have to try harder than that.
我可是艾丽卡·奥特加斯
I'm Erica Ortegas.
无敌舵手
I fly the ship.
撑住 有我在呢
Hold on. I got you.
我们尽力了
We did all we could.
现在要看巴特尔舰长自己了
It's in Captain Batel's hands now.
的确
Indeed.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没有你的话 我没法做到这一切
I couldn't have done that without you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
她怎么样了
How is she?
她在实验室里 仍在恢复中
She's in the lab, still in recovery.
外勤队已经救回
Landing Party accounted for and
正在应急医务室中接受治疗
getting treatment in the overflow infirmary.
艾丽卡伤得很重
Erica is critical...
但目前稳定
but stable.
谢谢你的通知
Thanks for the update.
一旦我们离开辐射区域
Once we clear the radiation bands,
就设定航线回地球 曲速回家
chart a course for Earth. Warp us home.
遵命 一号完毕
Of course. Number One out.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 主
Okay, Dad.
你赢了
You win.
我们
Our Father,
在天上的主
who art in heaven...
克里斯
Chris?
你醒了
You're awake.
是啊 我想这意味着
Yeah. Which I assume means
那些小戈恩们还没破肚而出
that tiny Gorn didn't pop out of my body
杀了大家呢
and kill everybody.
不
No.
当然没有 我们都好好的呢
No, no, no. We're still here.
史波克和查普尔想出了治疗方案
Spock and Chapel came up with a treatment, uh...
我后面会让他们解释给你听
I'll have them walk you through it later, but...
但你还没有完全脱离危险
...you're still not out of the woods yet.
怎么做到的
How?
乌娜帮的忙
Una helped.
克里斯 你就不应该那么做
Chris, you shouldn't have done that.
玛丽 我已经失去了太多 好吗
Marie, I've already lost too much, all right?
所以我们可以继续争
So we can sit here and we can argue about
争论未来会不会发生什么
what might or might not happen in the future,
但能不能把那些都放一边 让我抱着你
or you can just set all that aside and let me hold you.
我真的不能再失去你
I really don't want to lose you.
没事了
I'm still here.
我还在呢